# Adam Bauer

South Wales, NY 14139 adambauer42\_u7s@indeedemail.com

+1 716 359 8432

Asynchronous learner who excels at problem solving, safety, and efficiency. Multifaceted manager with years of experience in multiple fields. Great with people of all ages, computers, and most importantly; getting the job done. Responsible worker in a group and individual setting. In-depth understanding of Microsoft Office, heavy machinery, mechanics and excels at meeting deadlines in a quick turn-around setting. Very interested in Environmental Sciences and conservation.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

## Work Experience

#### Founder/ Executive Director

Respice Finem Inc.

October 2021 to Present

- · Founded on the idea Unity through education
- · Developed and marketed all designs for corporate needs
- · Banking and accounting of all operations
- $\cdot$  Manages all grant research and writing
- · Executes legal operations

### **Construction Supervisor**

716 Improvement LLC May 2014 to Present

- · Spearheaded with owner to manage all projects and crew members
- · Oversee work includes all types of common and specialty renovations and remodels
- · Manage employee timecards and expense reports
- · Create billing and purchase orders

#### **Business Development Associate**

Shell Fab

December 2020 to March 2021

- · Responsible for billing and paying vendors, customers, and suppliers
- · Problem solving with multiple tech organizations to receive best possible technology/price for the company
- · Responsible for finding and accruing new sales leads
- · Responsible for communicating with customer, vendors, suppliers to appropriate materials for each job
- · Drafting and designing marketing campaigns and informational flyers for suppliers, manufacturers, and customers

#### Conductor

Norfolk Southern - Buffalo, NY January 2018 to August 2020  $\cdot$  Trained under 100% rule compliancy adhering to all governing train movement and operation laws and rules submitted by

Norfolk and the FRA

- · Conducted the transporting of trains from point A to final destination, coordinated between crew and yard/train masters to perform at the most efficient level
- $\cdot$  Evaluated for knowing and complying with road and yard characteristic to ensure safe movement of trains

### **Assistant Terminal Manager of Pacific Rail Services**

Buffalo, NY

July 2016 to December 2019

- · Promoted to Manager after developing and implementing new schedule for employees, cutting overtime by 27%
- · Developed excel spreads to calculate metrics and maintain our monthly goals
- · Identified and on-boarded new employees, to accommodate Terminal contract growth
- · Managed employees to meet strict deadlines while adhering to complex safety standards

#### Education

### **Certificate in CS50 for Artificial Intelligence**

Harvard

Present

### **Certificate in Python for Artificial Intelligence**

MIT

Present

#### **Bachelor's Degree in Informatics**

University at Albany - Albany, NY

Present

### **Advanced Regents Diploma**

West Seneca East Senior Highschool

#### **Certificate in Full Stack Development**

Udemy - Buffalo, NY

#### Skills

- · Problem Solving
- Negotiation
- · Project Management
- Hiring
- Customer Services
- Excel Spreadsheets
- Microsoft Word
- Adobe

- Team Leadership
- · Critical thinking
- · Human resources
- Time-management
- Administration
- Safety
- Implementation
- Sales
- Billing
- Marketing development and research
- · Grant research
- Environmental Sciences
- Business Development
- Construction
- Java
- Python
- CSS
- Django
- Management
- Git
- JavaScript
- MySQL
- GitHub
- REST
- User Interface (UI)
- Node.js

## Assessments

## Attention to detail — Highly Proficient

March 2020

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: Highly Proficient

## Analyzing data — Proficient

November 2020

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data Full results: Proficient

## Working with MS Word documents — Highly Proficient

November 2020

Knowledge of various Microsoft Word features, functions, and techniques

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

## **Administrator** — **Familiar**

October 2020

Personality and problem-solving skills

Full results: <u>Familiar</u>

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.